# **EMMANUEL ILIVIEDA**

Email: ilivieda1@yahoo.com

**Phone:** 07085581974

Address: 5, Shotiminu Street, Ojokoro Extension, Agric, Ikorodu, Lagos State.

# **Summary**

I am a seasoned backend applications developer with 3 years experience developing highperformance applications. I have a strong understanding of the .net framework and am proficient in C# programming language. I have a keen eye for clean architecture design and a passion on the backend to enable good user experience. I am well-versed in agile development methodologies and looking to my challenge.

# **Experience**

Sep 2022 - Present .Net Software Engineer

The Bulb Africa

Create requirements and design specifications from high-level requirements, design and implement high-quality software from requirements with experience of building API(s), solid knowledge of .NET Core fundamentals and C#, and worked to build and maintain

Jun 2020 - Present

.Net Backend Software Engineer

Envivo Communications Limited

Planning and implementing game functionality, transforming design ideas into functional games, designing and building game codes. Identifying and fixing code errors and game bottlenecks, testing game functionality and theme dynamics,

## **Education**

2015 - 2016

Ladoke Akintola University of Technology, Ogbomoso, Oyo State

Master of Business Administration, Management and Accounting

Second Class Upper

#### FEDERAL UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY AKURE

Bachelor of Technology, Agricultural economics and extension

Third Class

# **Skills**

Github, Docker, Angular, SQL Server, Postman, DevOps, CI/CD, Typescript, T SQL, Swagger, Entity Framework, Git(bash), MAUI, Xamarin Forms, Dapper, Asp.Net Framework, Asp.Net Core, Razor/Blazor, Clean Architecture, Unity Game Engine, C#/C /Typescript/Dart/Html/Css

### **Hobbies**

Reading, meditating, playing guitar.

# **Portfolio**

https://github.com/Kadesh-Shyne?tab=repositories

www.linkedin.com/in/ilivieda-emmanuel-659393123